>> There are a number of
ways to interact with Azure
and automate the building and
configuration of services.
There are Azure SDKs,
Azure provides a number of
software development kits,
SDKs to help you get up and
running on developing on
Azure as quickly as possible.
Such as for,.NET, Java,
Node, Python, PHP and Go.
And there are many
more development tools
details of which are available
on azure.microsoft.com
or in github.com/azure.
There are also REST APIs,
Representational State Transfer.
REST APIs are service
endpoints that support
sets of HTTP operations or
methods which provide Create,
Review, Update, or Delete Access
to the service's resources.
Azure provides a comprehensive set of
REST APIs for Azure services
which are available to use.
Azure Cloud Shell is also available
as a management interface.
Azure Cloud Shell is a browser based
scripting environment for
interacting with Azure.
It provides the
flexibility of choosing
the shell experience that
best suits the way you work.
And it's accessible from anywhere
using the latest versions
of the following browsers,
Microsoft Edge, Microsoft
Internet Explorer,
Chrome, Firefox, or Safari.
Linux users can opt
for a Bash experience,
while Windows users can
opt for PowerShell.
You can access
the Cloud Shell from within
the Azure Portal or via
https//shell.azure.com.
Azure also supports the use of
Package Management Solutions
with Azure resources.
Package Management allows you to
install all the software you need
into your VM during or
after its deployment.
It's possible to manage all aspects
of software such as Installation,
Configuration, Upgrade,
and Uninstall.
And there's a wide range of
packaged software available for you
to install and use using
the Package Managers.
There are a number of
Package Management Solutions
available for you to
use depending on your environment
and needs some of which are,
APT is the Package Management
Solution for Debian
Linux environments.
YUM is the Package Management
Solution for CentOS
Linux environments.
And Chocolatey is
a Package Management Solution
for Windows built on PowerShell.