>> Azure Resource Manager is
a management layer in which
resource groups and all of the
resources within it are created,
configured, managed, and deleted.
It provides a consistent
management layer
which allows you to automate
the deployment and configuration
of resources using
different automation
scripting tools such
as Azure PowerShell,
Azure command-line interface,
the Azure portal,
Rest APIs, and Client SDKs.
With Azure Resource Manager,
you can deploy application
resources, update, manage,
and delete all the resources
for your solution in
a single coordinated operation.
An Azure Resource Manager
template precisely
defines all the Resource Manager
resources in a deployment.
You can deploy
a Resource Manager template
into a resource group
in a single operation.
Resource Manager templates
are declarative
in nature and written in JSON format.
By using a template,
you can repeatedly deploy
your solution through
its lifecycle in development,
test, and production
type environments,
and have confidence your resources
are deployed in a consistent state.
The benefits of using
Resource Manager templates include;
Improved consistency.
Make it easier to express and define
complex code deployments and
relationships between resources.
Reduce manual error prone tasks.
Support infrastructure as
code principles including
version control,
traceability, and modularization,
and promote re-use.
A template consists of
the following components;
Parameters, where you specify
which values are configurable
when the template runs.
Variables, where you define
values that are used
throughout the template.
Functions, here you define
procedures that you can re-use
throughout the template.
Resources, where you define
the Azure resources that
make up your deployment.
Outputs, where you define
any information you'd like to
receive when the template runs,
such as data generated at run time.
For example, a fully
qualified domain name.