>> To fully implement infrastructure
and configuration as code,
the application code of scripts,
definitions,text files and other
related files that are required for
deployment and configuration
must be version controlled.
Version Control has
the following characteristics:
Provides for accessing
version differences,
so, ways to visualize
differences between versions.
Provides traceability,
so, ways to see
versions and check in history
at any given point in time,
including who made the
changes and what was changed.
Provide branching, which allows
for work to be done in parallel
and in a distributed manner
through merges and branches,
modern Dev teams can
be pretty global.
In DevOps, both
the Development Team and
the Operations Team should be
using the same source control.
Everything should be
source controlled,
including source code,
environmental definitions,
infrastructure configuration,
deployment scripts,
documentation, and tests such
as unit tests and
integration tests etc.
In short, everything.
So that Dev and Ops
can work together,
run a particular version through
the deployment pipeline and get what
you're expecting each
time without error.
Some best practices for
working with Version Control
include: Setting up
an appropriate branching strategy.
A general role is to promote
the simplest branching strategy
possible to keep maintenance
low on sustainability high.
Connecting work to code.
An easy way to verify
that the applied code has
value and is related to
work on the backlog,
writing in code that does not
tie back to any work items,
is by linking work items
to code changes so that
metadata is kept with
the changes and then would
build in deployment.