>> If you've ever
received the middle of
the night emergency support call
because of a crushed server,
you know the pain of searching
through multiple spreadsheets,
or even your memory,
to access the manual steps of
setting up a new machine
from scratch.
There's also an age-old
difficulty of keeping
the development and production
environments consistent.
An easier way to remove
the possibility of human error when
initializing machines is to treat
environments and
infrastructure like code,
so that they are stored up from
a single consistent definition
termed infrastructure as code.
A common analogy for using
infrastructure as code
is the distinction between
owning pets and cattle.
When you own pets,
you give them names,
you treat them individually,
and if something bad happens
to them, you care a lot.
If you have a herd of cattle,
you might still name them,
but you treat them as a herd.
In infrastructure terms, without
treating environments as code,
there might be severe implications
of machine crashes,
and you need to replace it,
which can be thought of as pets.
If you use an infrastructure
as code model,
if a machine goes down,
you can just spin up
another machine with no issues,
which can be thought of as cattle.
A quick comparison of
manual deployments
versus deployments through
an infrastructure as code model
shows the benefits of using
infrastructure as code as
including consistency
of environments,
no snowflake servers,
every snowflake being unique,
and thus difficult to
reproduce manager maintain.
Environments being
more easily degraded
and scalable with
infrastructure as code.
Code being reusable across
different deployment environments.
So, there's a reuse benefit.
The ability to implement
an immutable infrastructure
model if you wish.
This is where servers are never
modified after data applied.
If a server needs to be
updated or modified,
a new server is built from
a common image, with the changes.
That's provisioned and tested,
and then replaces the old server,
the old server being decommissioned.
An ability to use
blue/green deployments,
sometimes referred to
as A/B deployments.
This is where you run
two identical environments,
only one of which is live,
serving public traffic.
Updates are delivered to
the idle environment,
not serving customer traffic.
Once updates have been tested and
verified, it is then pushed live,
and the original live environment
becomes the idle environment,
where the process is being
reversed for future updates.
So, we have a lot more control over
how we release
when infrastructure as code.
Also, a quicker release cadence
is possible when treating
infrastructure as code.