>> Configuration management refers to
the automated management
of configuration,
typically in the form of
version control scripts for
an application on
all the environments
and infrastructure
needed to support it.
Configuration management
means lighter weight,
executable configurations
that allow us
to have configuration on
environment scripted and automated.
For instance, adding
a new port to a firewall,
should be done by editing a text file
and running the release pipeline,
not by remoting into the environment
and spending on app manually.
Generally, managing the configuration
of one application in
an environment can be challenging.
So, scaling this out for
applications across multiple servers
is very difficult to do
without using the Configuration
as Code type model.
A quick comparison of
manual deployments versus
deployments through a Configuration
as Code type model include;
bugs being more easily reproduced
with a Configuration
as Code type model.
Configuration as Code providing
better traceability and
a means of auditing changes.
Consistent configuration.
Configuration as Code
being less error prone.
Increased deployment cadence,
less documentation needed and
needing to be maintained as
all configuration is
available in scripts.
It's easier to scale with
automatic configuration.
Also, just be aware that
the term Configuration as
Code is not used widely.
More widely used is
configuration management.
In some cases, Infrastructure
as Code is used to
describe both provisioning and
the configuration of environments.