>> Azure PowerShell is
a module that you add
to Windows PowerShell,
or PowerShell Core to let you
connect to your Azure subscription
on managed resources.
Azure PowerShell requires
PowerShell in order to function.
PowerShell provide services
like the shell window,
command parsing and so on.
An Azure PowerShell as the
Azure specific commands.
The base PowerShell product is
available in two different formats.
PowerShell on Windows
this comes by default in
Windows environments
or PowerShell Core.
A cross-platform version
of PowerShell that
can be installed
a Windows, Linux, or Mac.
Azure PowerShell is also accessible
via two different methods.
Firstly, via local install,
on Windows, Linux, or Mac.
The same as the base
PowerShell product or
via any browser using the
Azure Cloud Shell service.
This is a browser-based
management console
providing boat a Bash on
the PowerShell experience.
In both cases, Azure PowerShell
can be run either interactively
issuing commands in
real-time providing input
as needed or scripted,
where everything is
predefined then executed.
Let's look briefly at some of
the core PowerShell components.
Firstly, there's Cmdlets:
PowerShell command are
just called Cmdlets.
Cmdlets follow a verb-noun
naming convention.
For example, Get-Process,
format-Table, Start-Service.
There's also a convention
for verb choice.
With Get to retrieve data,
Set to insert or update data,
Format to format data,
and Out to direct outputs
to a destination, and more.
There also PowerShell modules.
Cmdlets are shipped in modules.
The PowerShell module is a DLL that
includes the code to process
each available Cmdlets.
You load Cmdlets into PowerShell
by loading the module
they are contained in.
You can obtain additional Cmdlets by
downloading specific modules
and installing them.
For example, the module
specific to Azure
provides the Cmdlets for
interacting with Microsoft Azure.
You can get a list
of loaded modules in
your PowerShell session using
the Cmdlets Get-module.