>> The Azure CLI is
a command line program
that you can use to connect to
Azure and to execute administrative
commands on Azure resources.
It runs on Linux,
Mac OS, and Windows,
and can also be used from a browser
through the Azure Cloud Shell.
Commands in the CLI are structured by
groups, sub-groups, and commands,
and we can see that layout
at the top level by
running the command Az--help.
We can see what's available under
the Az group by scrolling
through the help output.
Here's the subgroups which
represent the Azure services,
and we could see services
such as app service,
IoT, VM, Web App, and many others.
By scrolling down through
the command section,
we see the commands available
to act on the group Az,
such as configure, find,
login, and others.
As you construct the commands,
each group represents
a service provided by Azure.
Under subgroups, divide commands for
these services into
logical groupings.
For example, let's look at
the Az vm group by running
the command az vm --help.
The Az Vm group contains subgroups
including availability set,
disk, image, nic and others.
As commands including
create, list and restart.
So, to restart a virtual machine
using the Azure CLI,
we would have a command
something like the following;
where az vm is the group
acting on the Azure
Virtual Machine service.
Restart is the command your
issuing against the group.
Then, there are two parameter values
that would be required
in this command,
for Resource Group and
Virtual Machine name.
The Azure CLI can be
used interactively,
issuing commands in realtime,
providing input as
needed or scripted,
where everything is
predefined then executed.