>> Let's check out some of
the common architecting
considerations when
looking to implement infrastructure
and configuration as code models.
Firstly is modularization.
So, how the various
components that define
your environmental structured or
reference such as text files,
definitions, script, et
cetera, can be important?
Over time, Azure applications
environments change and
complexity increases,
it can become more
difficult to manage,
maintain or troubleshoot
your automation files.
For small to medium solutions
with small teams,
having single file to define
application resources and
configuration can be fun,
and maybe easier to
understand the maintain.
It's possible to see
all the resources
and values in a single file,
so there can be benefits to
this scenario in certain situations.
However, for advanced
more complex scenarios,
breaking all automation
resources into
their constituent parts
is of major benefit.
This can be referred to
as modularization or
modularizing your automation
assets into the component parts,
which collectively
defined environments
and configuration for
your application.
Some of the benefits of
modularization include,
easier to reuse components
across different scenarios,
easier to manage and
maintain your code,
and it's easier to extend
an Azure existing
infrastructure definitions.
Now, let's look at imperative
versus declarative models
for automation.
There are a few types of
approaches to implementing
infrastructure and configuration
as code which you can adopt.
Two of the main methods of
approach are; declarative.
The declarative approach states
what the final state should be,
without defining how
that final state should be achieved.
Imperative. In
the imperative approach,
we define what
the final state needs to be,
but also include how to
achieve that final state.
The declarative approach
abstracts away
the methodology of how
a state is achieved,
and as such, it can be easier to
read and understand
what is being done,
as well as making it easier
to write and define.
A declarative approach
would generally be
preferred option for ease of use.
Azure Resource Manager
templates would be
an example automation file
using a declarative approach.
Now, let's look at Idempotency.
Idempotence is a mathematical
term that can be
used in the context of infrastructure
and configuration as code.
Where there is the ability to apply
one or more operations
against the resource,
resulting in the same outcome.
In essence, if you apply
a deployment to a set of
resources a 1,000 times,
you'll end up with the same result
after each application
a descriptor template.
Idempotency can be
achieved in two ways,
automatically configuring
and reconfiguring
an existing set of resources
or discarding to existing resources
and recreating a fresh environment.
So, using an immutable
infrastructure model
where infrastructure is not
modified after it is applied.
When the finding infrastructure
and configuration as code,
it'll be best practice to build
those scripts and templates
in such a way as to
embrace Idempotency.
Then there's Technical Debt.
Technical Debt is
the set of problems in
a development effort
that make progress on
customer value inefficient or costly.
It creates Unplanned
work blocks progress.
It can start small and grow
significantly over time,
through rush changes and the lack
of context and discipline.
It can ultimate materialize
out of nowhere,
even for a project regarded as clean,
because of changes in
projects circumstances.
Technical Debt includes anything
the team must do to deploy
production quantity code and
keep it running in production.
Examples of technical
debt can be; bugs,
accessibility, changing
technologies or
versions which are not accounted
for as part of your dev process.
You can think of technical debt and
loose terms as the taking
of a shortcut,
be it intended or unintended.
Technical debt is not
necessarily eliminated,
rather it is managed.
Some considerations of managing
technical debt include,
understanding and
identifying the debt
and where it is located in the code,
as well as evaluating
the cost to fix it.
There are tools that can
be used to help with this.
Putting policies in place focused on
preventing debt from getting
worse and managing it down,
such as allowing for
the periodic updates of
Resource Management templates
for new API versions,
and doing that as part of
your general development work.
Tracking debt over time to ensure
it's trending down in
the right direction,
and meeting defined policies,
prioritizing debt along with
new application features
and desired functionality.
Finally, let's look at
Configuration Drift.
Configuration Drift is the process
whereby set of resources
changed her state over time,
from what was the original state
in which they were deployed.
Over time, each environment
may become a snowflake,
or unique configuration that cannot
be reproduced automatically.
With snowflakes,
administration and maintenance
of infrastructure involves
manual processes,
which are hard to track
and contribute to errors.
Configuration Drift
may also introduce
security vulnerabilities
into environments.
For example, parts being opened are
intended to be closed, updates,
security patch has not been
applied consistently
across environments,
or software installed that
does not meet your
compliance requirements.
It can be difficult to completely
eliminate Configuration Drift,
but there are many ways you can
manage it in your environments,
using Configuration Management tools
and products such as;
Windows PowerShell
Desired State Configuration,
which is a management
platform in PowerShell
allowing you to manage and
enforce Resource Configurations,
Azure Policy, which is
an Azure service that enforces
policies and compliance standards
for Azure resources.
There are also many other
non Microsoft solutions
that can be integrated
with Microsoft Azure.
To help deal with
Configuration Drift.