>> Azure Resource Manager is
a management layer on which
resource groups and all the
resources within it are created,
configured, managed, and deleted.
It provides a consistent
management layer
which allows you to
automate the deployment and
configuration of resources using
different automation scripting tools,
such as, Azure PowerShell,
Azure command-line interface,
the Azure portal, REST
APIs, and Client SDKs.
With Azure Resource Manager
you can deploy
application resources,
update, manage,
and delete all the resources
for your solution in
a single coordinated operation.
An Azure Resource Manager
template precisely
defines all the resource manager
resources in a deployment.
You can deploy
a Resource Manager template
into a resource group
in a single operation.
Resource Manager templates
are declarative
in nature on written in JSON format.
By using a template,
you can repeatedly deploy
your solution through its lifecycle,
and development test and
production type environments,
and have confidence your resources
are deployed in a consistent state.
The benefits of using
Resource Manager templates include;
improved consistency. Making it
easier to express and define
complex co-deployments and
relationships between resources.
Reduce manual error-prone tasks.
Support infrastructure as
code principles including
version control,
traceability, and modularization,
and promote re-use.
A template consists of the
following components: Parameters,
where you specify which values are
configurable when the template runs.
Variables, where you define
values that are used
throughout the template.
Functions, here you define
procedures that you can re-use
throughout the template.
Resources, where you define
the Azure resources that
make up your deployment.
Outputs, where you
define any information
you'd like to receive
when the template runs,
such as data generated at runtime.
For example, a fully
qualified domain name.